<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RCUBSyllabus</string>
    <string name="tempadid">ca-app-pub-9323377994714094/1107399513</string>
    <string name="interadid">ca-app-pub-9323377994714094/4672800501</string>

    //MAINACTIVITY

    <string name="first">First Sem</string>
    <string name="second">Second Sem</string>
    <string name="third">Third Sem</string>
    <string name="fourth">Fourth Sem</string>
    <string name="fifth">Fifth Sem</string>

    <string name="sixth">Sixth Sem</string>

    //MINACTIVITY

    //FIRSTSEM

    <string name="maths">Mathematics-I</string>
    <string name="english1">Basic English</string>
    <string name="compfundamentals">Computer Fundamentals</string>
    <string name="C">Programming in C</string>
    <string name="ic">Indian Constitution</string>
    <string name="account">Financial Accountancy</string>

    //FIRSTSEM

    //SECONDSEM

    <string name="finman">Financial Management</string>
    <string name="mat2">Mathematics -II</string>
    <string name="eng2">Add. English</string>
    <string name="c2">Data Structures Using C</string>
    <string name="dlcs">Digital Logic and  Computer Design</string>
    <string name="hres">Human Rights and Environmental Studies</string>

    //SECONDSEM

    //THIRDSEM

    <string name="coa">Computer Organization and Architecture</string>
    <string name="cpp">OOPS Using C++</string>
    <string name="dms">Discrete Mathematical Structures</string>
    <string name="unix">Introduction to UNIX</string>
    <string name="pd">Personality Development and Communication Skills</string>

    //THIRDSEM

    //FOURTHSEM

    <string name="daa">Design and Analysis of Algorithms</string>
    <string name="java">Programming Using Java</string>
    <string name="it">IT Infrastructure and Management</string>
    <string name="se">Software Engineering</string>
    <string name="vb">VB.Net</string>

    //FOURTHSEM

    //FIFTHSEM

    <string name="os">Operating System</string>
    <string name="wp">Web Programming</string>
    <string name="dbms">Database Management Systems</string>
    <string name="cn">Computer Networks</string>
    <string name="cnet">.Net Framework Using C#</string>

    //FIFTHSEM

    //SIXTHSEM

    <string name="spt">Software Practices and Testing</string>
    <string name="bi">Business Intelligence</string>
    <string name="j2ee">J2EE</string>
    <string name="lab">Lab1: J2EE and Software Testing Laboratory</string>
    <string name="project">Project and viva - voce</string>

    //SIXTHSEM

    //FIRSTSYLLABUS

    <string name="math1">
        "UNIT I\n\n"
        "Complex Numbers:Complex Numbers; Conjugate of a complex number; modulus of a complex Number;"
        "geometrical representation of complex number; De Moivere’s theorem; nth roots of a complex number.\n\n"

        "UNIT II\n\n"
        "Sequence and Series: Arithmetic Progression (A.P.), Arithmetic Mean (A.M.), Geometric Progression"
        "(G.P.), general term of a G.P., sum of n terms of a G.P. Arithmetic and geometric series, infinite G.P. and"
        "its sum, geometric mean (G.M.). Relation between A.M. and G.M.\n\n"

        "UNIT III\n\n"
        "Binomial Theorem: Statement of the binomial theorem for positive integral indices, general and middle"
        "term in binomial expansion, simple applications."
        "Quadratic Equations: Solution of Quadratic Equations by factor method, complete square method, and"
        "Discriminant method, Relation of the roots.\n\n"

        "UNIT IV\n\n"
        "Introduction to Trigonometry: Trigonometry, The theorem of Pythagoras, Trigonometric ratios of acute"
        "angles, Evaluating trigonometric ratios, Solution of right-angled triangles, Angles of elevation and"
        "depression, Sine and cosine rules, Area of any triangle."
        "Vectors: Scalars and vectors, addition of two vectors, vector subtraction, scalar and vector products.\n\n"

        "UNIT V\n\n"
        "Co-ordinate Geometry: Distance formulae, section formulae, shifting of origin. Slope of a line and angle"
        "between two lines. Various forms of equations of a line: parallel to axes, point slope form, slope-intercept"
        "form, two-point form, intercepts form and normal form. General equation of a line.Equation of family of"
        "lines passing through the point of intersection of two lines.Distance of a point from a line.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="eng">
        "<u>BASIC ENGLISH\n\n</u>"
        "Text: Seven One-Act Plays (Ed), K.S. Ramamurthy: OUP\n"
        "Only the following plays are to be studied.\n"
        "1. The Seven Slaves - A. Ball\n"
        "2. One Good Turn – A.E.M. Bayliss\n"
        "3. Night Watches – Allan Monkhouse\n"
        "4. The Unexpected – Ella Adkins\n"
        "5. Sunday Costs Five Pesos – Josephina Niggli\n\n"
        "Grammar and Composition"\n\n"
        "Modals (Making Sentences using Modals)\n"
        "Sentence Linkers (Making Sentences using Linkers)\n"
        "Use of words, phrases and idioms\n"
        "Describing a situation (Marriage, Birthday, Local fair, temple festivals, national\n"
        "festivals, Funerals etc.)\n\n"

        "Pattern of Question Paper\n"

        "(80 Marks per paper of three hours and 20 Marks for I.A)\n"
        "1) Objective type questions on the play\n"
        "2) Reference to Context\n"
        "3) Essay type question on the plays (one out of two)\n"
        "4) Essay type question on the plays (one out of two)\n"
        "5) Short Notes on the plays (two out of four)\n"
        "6) A) Modals Make sentences using given modals 5 out of 7\n"
        "B) Sentence Linkers\n"
        "Make sentences using given sentence linkers 5 out of 7\n"
        "7) A) Use of words, phrases and idioms\n"
        "3 Marks for Use of Words, 3 Marks for Phrases and"
        "4 marks for Idioms and Phrases\n"
        "B) Describing a situation (about 200 words)\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="compfun">
     "UNIT I\n\n"
        "Introduction: Computer, data processing, characteristic features of computers, computer evolution to"
        "present form, computer generation."
        "Basic computer organization: Basic operations performed by computers, basic organization of computer"
        "system, input units and its functions, output units and its functions, storage units and its functions, types"
         "of storage.\n\n"

        "UNIT II\n\n"

        "Number systems: non-positional number system, positional number system, decimal, binary, octal, and"
        "hexadecimal number systems. Conversion from decimal to binary and vice-versa."
        "Computer Codes: Computer data, computer codes: representation of data in binary, commonly used"
        "computer codes, collating sequence."
        "Computer arithmetic: Basic arithmetic operations using binary numbers.\n\n"

        "UNIT III\n\n"
        "Processor and memory: Internal structure of processor, memory structure, types of processors, main"
        "memory organization, random access memory, read only memory, cache memory."
        "Secondary storage: secondary storage devices and their needs, commonly used secondary storage devices,"
        "sequential and direct access storage devices, basic principles of commonly used secondary storage"
        "devices (magnetic disk, optical disk, flash drives, memory card, disk array)."
        "IO devices: commonly used input output(IO) devices.\n\n"

        "UNIT IV\n\n"
        "Software: Software and its relationship with hardware, types of softwares, relationship among hardware,"
        "system software, application software and users of computer systems, steps involved in software"
        "development, firmware, middleware."
        "Application software case study: MS-Word: editing and formatting documents."
        "Overview of operating system: Definition, functions of operating system, concept of multiprogramming,"
        "multitasking, multithreading, multiprocessing, time-sharing, real time, single-user and multi-user operating"
        "system.\n\n"


        "UNIT V\n\n"
        "Windows OS- Basics of Windows, basic components of windows, icons, taskbar, activating windows,"
        "using desktop, title bar, running applications, exploring computer, managing files and folders, copying"
        "and moving files and folders. Control panel – display properties, adding and removing software and"
        "hardware.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="cc">
       "UNIT I\n\n"

       "Programming Languages and its Classification, Compiler, Interpreter, Linker, Loader."
        "Problem Solving: Problem Identification, Analysis, flowcharts, Pseudo codes and algorithms,"
        "Program Coding, Program Testing and Execution. Examples of flow charts and algorithms- Largest"
        "of three numbers, reversing the digits of an integer, base conversion, GCD of two integers,"
        "generating prime numbers, sine function computation, computing nth Fibonacci numbers.\n\n"

"UNIT II\n\n"
"Overview of C: C character set, identifiers and keywords, Data types, Constants and Variables,"
"Assignment statement, Symbolic constant, Structure of a C Program, printf(), scanf() Functions,"
"Operators and Expression: Arithmetic, relational, logical, bitwise, unary, assignment, shorthand"
"assignment operators, conditional operators and increment and decrement operators, Arithmetic"
"expressions, evaluation of arithmetic expression, type casting and conversion, operator hierarchy and"
"associativity.\n\n"

"UNIT III\n\n"
"Decision making and branching: Decision making with IF statement, IF-ELSE statement, Nested IF"
"statement, ELSE-IF ladder, switch statement, goto statement. Decision making and looping: For, while,"
"and do-while loop, jumps in loops - break, continue statement, Nested loops."
"Functions: Standard Mathematical functions, Input/output: Unformatted and formatted I/O function"
"in C. User defined functions: definition, prototype, Local and global variables, passing parameters,"
"recursion.\n\n"

"UNIT IV\n\n"
"Arrays, strings and pointers: Definition, types, initialization, processing an array, passing arrays to"
"functions, Array of Strings. String constant and variables, Declaration and initialization of string,"
"Input/output of string data, Storage classes in C: auto, extern, register and static storage class, their"
"scope, storage, and lifetime."
"String Handling: String Library Functions: strlen, strcat, strcmp, strcpy, strrev.\n\n"

"UNIT V\n\n"
"Structure amd Union: Definition of Structure, Declaring Structure, Accessing Structure Elements, Array"
"of Structure, Nesting of Structure. Definition of Union, declaring and using Union.Difference"
"between Structure amd Union."
"Error Handling during I/O Operations, Command Line Arguments, Documentation, debugging, C"
"Processors, Macros.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="i">
"UNIT I\n\n"
"Significance of the constitution: Making of the Constitution role of the Constituent Assembly, Salient"
"features, the Preamble, Citizenship, Procedure for amendment of the Constitution.\n\n"

"UNIT II\n\n"
"Fundamentals Rights: the Right to Equality, the Right to Freedom, the Right against Exploitation , the"
"Right to Freedom of Religion, Cultural and Educational Rights, the Right to Constitutional Remedies.\n\n"

"UNIT III\n\n"
"Nature of the Directive Principles of State Policy, difference between of Fundamental rights and Directive"
"principles of State Policy – Implementation of Directive Principles of State Policy, Fundamental Duties.\n\n"

"UNIT IV\n\n"
"Union Government – Powers and Functions of the President, the Prime Minister, Council of"
"Ministers.Composition, powers and functions of the Parliament, Organization of Judiciary, Jurisdiction of"
"the Supreme Court, Independence of Judiciary.\n\n"

"UNIT V\n\n"
"State Government – Powers and Functions of Governor, Chief Minister, Council of"
"Ministers.Composition, Powers and functions of State Legislature, Local Government and the"
"Constitution, Relation between the Union and the states.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="acc">
        "UNIT I\n\n"
        "Basic Accounting Concepts: Background of Accounting, Introduction, importance and scope, Accounts –"
        "Types and classification; basic terms– Capital, Income, Expenditure, Expenses, Assets, Liabilities and"
        "application to Problems., Accounting Equation, Double Entry System. Generallyaccepted accounting"
        "principles.\n\n"

        "UNIT II\n\n"
        "Journal and Ledger- Journal and recording of entries in journal with narration; Ledger –Posting from"
        "Journal to respective ledger accounts. Basic concepts of purchase book, sales book and cashbook. Trial"
        "Balance: Need and objectives; Application of Trial Balance; different types of errors escaped, trial"
        "Balance preparation.\n\n"

        "UNIT III\n\n"
        "Final Accounts: Final Accounts without adjustments. Understanding of final accounts of a"
        "Company.Important provisions of Companies Act, 2013 in respect of preparation of Final Accounts.\n\n"

        "UNIT IV\n\n"
        "Reconciliation and Depreciation: Bank Reconciliation Statement, Methods of Depreciation: Straight line"
        "Methods, Reducing Balance Method, Change in Depreciation Method. Preparation of simple bank"
        "reconciliation statement.\n\n"

        "UNIT V\n\n"
        "Computerised Accounting: Computers and Financial application, Accounting Software packages.An"
        "overview of computerized accounting system - Salient features and significance, Concept of grouping of"
        "accounts, Codification of accounts, maintaining the hierarchy of ledger, Generating Accounting Reports.\n\n"
 </string>
    //SECONDSEM

    //THIRDSEM

    <string name="finman1">
"UNIT I\n\n"
"The Role of Management Accounting, Management Accounting Framework, Functions of"
"Management Accounting,Tools of Management Accounting,The Balanced Scorecard, Cost"
"Management System, Value Added Concept , Merits of Management Accounting , Demerits of"
"Management Accounting , Distinction between Management Accounting and Financial Accounting.\n\n"

"UNIT II\n\n"
"Financial Statement Analysis: Meaning of Ratio, Steps in Ratio Analysis,Classification of Ratios, Du"
"Pont Chart , Solved Problems , Advantages of Ratio Analysis, Limitation of Ratio analysis"
"Funds Flow Analysis: Meaning of Funds Flow Statement, Ascertainment of flow of funds, Technique"
"of preparing funds flow statement, Schedule of Changes in Working Capital, Adjusted Profit and Loss"
"account, Funds Flow Statement.\n\n"

"UNIT III\n\n"
"Cash Flow Analysis: Meaning of Cash Flow Statement , Purpose of Cash Flow Statement , Preparation"
"of Cash Flow Statement , Format of Cash Flow Statement, Cash Flow from Operating Activities , Cash"
"Flow Statement under Direct Method , Different between Cash Flow Analysis and Fund Flow"
"Analysis, Uses of Cash Flow Statement"
"Understanding Cost: Meaning of Cost, Objective of Costing, Methods of Costing, Technique of"
"Costing, Classification of Cost, Elements of Cost, Statement of Cost Sheet, Solved Problems.\n\n"

"UNIT IV\n\n"
"Marginal Costing and Break Even Analysis: Introduction, Concept of Marginal Costing,"
"Characteristics of Marginal Costing , Difference between Absorption Costing and Marginal Costing ,"
"Marginal Cost, Contribution, Cost Volume Profit (CVP) Analysis, Break Even Chart , Break Even"
"Point, Profit Volume ratio or MCSR , Target profit , Margin of Safety , Application of Marginal cost ,"
"Limitations of Marginal cost, Solved Problems.\n\n"

"UNIT V\n\n"
"Joint Stock Company - Meaning, Definition, Objectives, Issue of Shares (Equity Shares and Preference"
"shares), Preparation of final Accounts, Trading account, profit and loss account, profit and loss"
"appropriation account and balance sheet."
"Decisions Involving Alternative Choices: Decision Making, Types of Costs, Types of Choices"
"Decisions, Make or Buy Decisions, Addition/Discontinuance of a Product line, Sell or Process Further,"
"Operate or Shut down, Exploring New Markets, Maintaining a desired level of profit.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="mat22">
"UNIT I\n\n"
"Infinite Series:Convergence and divergence of infinite series, Comparison Test , D’Alembert’s Ratio"
"Test, Gauss Test, Raabe’s test, Logarithmic Test, Cauchy’s Root Test, Alternating series, Conditional"
"convergence and absolute convergence.\n\n"

"UNIT II\n\n"
"Determinants: Definition, Minors, Cofactors, Properties of Determinants."
"Matrices: Definition, Types of Matrices, Addition, Subtraction, Scalar Multiplication and"
"Multiplication of Matrices, Adjoint, Inverse, Cramers Rule, Rank of Matrix, Dependence of Vectors,"
"Eigen Vectors of a Matrix, Caley-Hamilton Theorem (without proof).\n\n"

"UNIT III\n\n"
"Limits and Continuity:Limit at a Point, Properties of Limit, Computation of Limits of Various Types of"
"Functions, Continuity at a Point, Continuity Over an Interval, Intermediate Value Theorem, Type of"
"Discontinuities\n\n"

"UNIT IV\n\n"
"Differentiation: Derivative, Derivatives of Sum, Differences, Product and Quotients, Chain Rule,"
"Derivatives of Composite Functions, Logarithmic Differentiation, Rolle’s Theorem, Mean Value"
"Theorem, Expansion of Functions (Maclaurin’s and Taylor’s), Indeterminate Forms, L’ Hospitals Rule,"
"Maxima and Minima, Curve Tracing, Successive Differentiation and Liebnitz Theorem.\n\n"

"UNIT V\n\n"
"Integration: Integral as Limit of Sum, Fundamental Theorem of Calculus( without proof.), Indefinite"
"Integrals, Methods of Integration Substitution, By Parts, Partial Fractions, Reduction Formulae for"
"Trigonometric Functions, Gamma and Beta Functions(definition).\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="eng22">
"Text: The Cutting Edge: Science and Scientists\n\n"
"(Ed. Colin Swatridge (Macmillan)\n"
"Only the following biographical sketches are to be taught.\n"
"1. Rene Descartes (1596-1650)\n"
"2. Antoine Lavoisier (1743-94)\n"
"3. Ivan Pavlov (1849-1926)\n"
"4. Sigmund Freud (1856-1939)\n"
"5. Werner Heisenberg (1901-1976)\n\n"

"Grammar and Composition\n"
"1) Relative Clauses\n"
"2) Conditionals and ‘wish’\n"
"3) Use of words as Two different forms of Speech\n"
"4) Report Writing (functions, seminars, excursion, tours, accident,"
"earthquake, flood, etc.)\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="dsc">
        "UNIT I\n\n"
        "Advanced C: Dynamic memory allocation and pointers in C- Declaring and initializing pointers,"
        "Pointer and Functions, Pointer and Arrays, Pointer and Strings, Pointer and Structure, Pointer to Pointer."
        "Static and dynamic memory allocation. Memory allocation functions :malloc, calloc, free and"
        "realloc. File Management in C: Defining and Opening and Closing File, Input and Output Operations on Files,"
        "Random Access to Files.\n\n"

        "UNIT II\n\n"
        "Introduction to Data structures: Definition, Classification of data structures: primitive and non-"
        "primitive. Operations on data structures Search: Basic Search Techniques- sequential search, Binary search- Iterative and Recursive methods."
        "Sort- General Background: Definition, different types: Bubble sort, Selection sort, Merge sort,"
        "Insertion sort, Quick sort.\n\n"

        "UNIT III\n\n"
        "Recursion: Definition, Recursion in C, Writing Recursive programs – Binomial coefficient,"
        "Fibonacci, GCD, towers of Hanoi."
        "Stack – Definition, Array representation of stack, Operations on stack-push and pop, Infix, prefix and"
        "postfix notations, Conversion of an arithmetic expression from Infix to postfix, applications of stacks.\n\n"

        "UNIT IV\n\n"
        "Queue - Definition, Array representation of queue, Types of queue: Simple queue, circular queue,"
        "double ended queue (deque) priority queue, operations on all types of Queues.\n\n"

        "UNIT V\n\n"
        "Linked list – Definition, components of linked list, representation of linked list, advantages and"
        "disadvantages of linked list, Arrays versus linked list, Types of linked list: Singly linked list, doubly"
        "linked list, Circular linked list and circular doubly linked list. Operations on singly linked list: creation,"
        "insertion, deletion, search and display. Implementation of stack and queues using linked list.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="dlcs2">

        "UNIT I\n\n"
        "Digital Systems and Binary Numbers: Digital Systems, Number systems and base conversions,"
        "Representation of signed Binary Numbers, Binary codes, binary logic.\n\n"

        "UNIT II\n\n"
        "Boolean Algebra: Introduction to Boolean Algebra, Axioms and Laws of Boolean Algebra, Boolean functions, Canonical"
        "and Standard Forms. Gate – Level Minimization: The Map method, Two, Three, Four Variable K-map’s, Don’t Care"
        "Conditions, NAND and NOR implementation, Exclusive OR function.\n\n"

        "UNIT III\n\n"
        "Combinational Logic: Combinational logic circuits, analysis and design procedure, Binary adder and"
        "subtractor, decimal adder, binary multiplier, Magnitude comparator, Decoders, Encoders,"
        "Multiplexers.\n\n"

        "UNIT IV\n\n"
        "Synchronous Sequential Logic: Sequential circuits, Latches, Flip Flops, SR, JK, T, D Flip Flops, Flip"
        "Flop excitation tables. Registers and Counters: Registers, Shift registers, Ripple counters, Synchronous counters, Other"
        "counters.\n\n"

        "UNIT V\n\n"
        "Memory and Programmable Logic: Random access memory, memory decoding, error detection and"
        "correction, Read-Only memory, Programmable logic array, Programmable array logic, sequential"
        "programmable devices.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="hres1">

        "Section A: Environmental Studies\n\n"

        "Nature of environmental studies:\n\n"
        "Definitions, scope and importance, Multidisciplinary nature of environmental studies need for public"
        "awareness. Natural resources and associated problems: (a) Forest resources : Use and over exploitation,"
        "deforestation timber extraction , mining , dams and their effects on forests and tribal people (b) Water"
        "resources : Use and over utilization of surface and ground water ,floods, drought, conflicts, over water,"
        "dams-benefits and problems (c) Mineral resources use exploitation, environmental effects of extracting"
        "and using mineral resources (d) Food resources: World food problems , changes caused by agriculture"
        "effects of modern agriculture, fertilizer problems(e) Energy resources : growing energy needs"
        "renewable and non-renewable energy sources , use of alternate energy sources (f) land resources: land"
        "as resources, and land degradation, man induced landslides, soil erosion and desertification. Role of an"
        "individual in conservation of natural resources.Equitable use of resources for sustainable lifestyles.\n\n"

"Ecosystem:\n\n"
"Concepts of an ecosystem,structure and function of an ecosystem,Production, consumer sand"
"de composers, Energy flow in the echo system , Ecological succession , Food chains,food webs and"
"ecological pyramids, Introduction , types Characteristics features , structures and functions of the"
"following echo system (a) Forest echo system (b) Grass land echo system(c) desert echo system (d)"
"Aquatic echo system (ponds , streams, lakes, rivers,oceans, estuaries).\n\n"

"Biodiversity and its conservation:\n\n"
"Introduction –definition: Generic, species and echo system diversity, bio geographical classification of"
"India, Value of biodiversity: consumptive use, productive use, social , ethical,aesthetic and option"
"value , Biodiversity at global , national and local levels, India as a mega diversity nation, Western ghat"
"as a bio-diversity, Hot spots of biodiversity. Threats to biodiversity: habitat loss, poaching of wildlife,"
"man wildlife conflicts, Endangered andendemic species of India , Conservation of biodiversity: In situ"
"and ex-situ , conservation of biodiversity.\n\n"

"Environmental Pollution:\n\n"
"Definition causes, effects and control measures of (a) Air pollution(b) Water pollution (c) Soil"
"pollution(d) Marine pollution (e) Noise pollution (f) Thermal pollution (g) Nuclear hazards,Solid"
"waste management : causes , effects and control measures urban and industrialwastes, Role of an"
"individual in prevention of pollution , Disaster management : Foodearthquake, cyclone and landslides,"
"Tsunami.\n\n"

"Social issues and Environment:\n\n"
"From Unsustainable to Sustainable development , urban problems related to energy ,"
"Waterconservation, rain water harvesting, watershed management, Resettlement andrehabilitation of"
"people ;its problems and concerns , Environmental ethics; Issues andpossible solutions , climate"
"change, global warming , acid rain, ozone layer depletion,nuclear accidents and holocaust, Wasteland"
"reclamation , consumerism and waste products, Environment protection Act, air (Prevention and"
"control of pollution) act Water (Preventionand control of pollution) Act, Wildlife protection act, Forest"
"conservation Act, Issues involvedin enforcement of environmental legislation public awareness.\n\n"


"Human Population and the Environment:\n\n"
"Population growth, variations among nations, Population explosion, family welfareprogramming,"
"Environment and human health, value Education, women and child welfare,Role of information"
"technology in environmental and human health.\n\n"

"Field work:\n\n"
"Visit to a local area to document environmental assets river /forest/grassland/hill/mountain,Visit to a"
"local polluted site Urban/Rural/Industrial/Agricultural, study of common plants,insects, birds, study of"
"simple echosystem ponds, river, hill slopes ,etc.\n\n"

        "Section B: Human Rights\n\n"


"Unit 1\n\n"
"Nature of human rights, origin and development of the concept of Human Rights, Functionsof Human"
"rights in modern society, Human rights and democratic governance; limitations ofHuman rights.\n\n"

"Unit 2\n\n"
"Classification of Human rights, Civil and political Rights-Nature and functions: Social andEconomics"
"Rights; Right of vulnerable groups such as women, children minorities, triable and the disabled,"
"Constitutional incorporation of Human rights in India.\n\n"

"Unit 3\n\n"
"Enforcement of human rights-basic principles governing enforcement of human rights atnational ,"
"regional and International levels , national Human rights , Commission-rganization, functions and"
"powers.\n\n"
    </string>

    //SECONDSEM

    //THIRDSEM

    <string name="coa1">

        "Unit I\n\n"
        "Number Systems, Digital Logic Circuits: Decimal number system, binary number system,"
"octal number system, hexadecimal number system, binary addition, binary subtraction, Logic gates,"
"Boolean algebra, map simplification, Half Adder, Full Adder, Subtractor, digital integrated circuits,"
"Decoders, Multiplexers.\n\n"

        "Unit II\n\n"
        "Register Transfer and Microoperations: Register transfer Language, Register Transfer, Bus"
"and memory Transfer, arithmetic micro operations, logic micro operations, shift micro operations and"
"Arithmetic Logic shift Unit.\n\n"

        "Unit III\n\n"
        "Basic Computer Organization and Design: Instruction codes, computer registers, computer"
"instructions, timing and control, instruction cycle, memory reference instructions, input output and"
"interrupt, Complete Computer Description.\n\n"

        "Unit IV\n\n"
        "Central Processing Unit: Introduction, general register organization, stack organization,"
"Instruction Formats, addressing modes, Data transfer and manipulation, program control.\n\n"

    "Unit V\n\n"
        "Input / Output Organization: Peripheral devices, I/O interface, asynchronous data transfer,"
"modes of transfer, priority interrupt, Direct Memory Access (DMA), Input-Output Processor (IOP), and"
"serial communication. Memory Organization: memory hierarchy, main memory, auxiliary memory,"
"associative memory, cache memory, virtual memory and memory management hardware.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="cpp1">
        "Unit I:\n\n"
        "Introduction: Procedural language ,definition of OOP , Basic concepts of OOP , Object , Class,"
"Data Abstraction, Data Encapsulation, Data Hiding member functions, Reusability, Inheritance ,"
"Creating new Data Types , Polymorphism, Overloading, Dynamic binding and Message passing. C++"
"Features: The iostream class, C++ Comments, C++ Keywords, Variable declaration, The Const"
"qualifier , The endl, Setw, set precision , Manipulators , The scope resolution operator , The new and"
"delete operators. Functions: Simple Functions , Function declaration, calling the functions, function"
"definition, passing argument to returning value from function; passing constants , variables, pass by"
"value, passing structure variables, pass by reference ,Default arguments , return statements, return by"
"reference , overloaded functions, different number of arguments ,different kinds of argument , inline"
"functions.\n\n"

"Unit II\n\n"
        "Objects and classes: Classes and objects, class declaration, class members; data"
"Constructors, Destructors, member functions, Class member visibility ;private, public, protected. The"
"scope of the class objects constructors; default constructor ,Constructor with argument , constructor"
"with default arguments , Dynamic constructor , copy constructor , Overloaded constructor , Objects as"
"function arguments ;member functions defined outside the class, objects as arguments, returning"
"objects from functions, class conversion, manipulating private Data members Destructors ,classes ,"
"objects and memory array as class member data, Array of objects , string as class member.\n\n"

"Unit III:\n\n"
        "Operator Overloading: Overloading unary operator; Operator keyword, Operator arguments,"
"operator return value, Nameless temporary objects, limitations of increment operator, overloading"
"binary operator ,arithmetic operators, comparison operator, arithmetic assignment operator, Data"
"conversion; conversion between Basic types , conversion between objects and basic types, conversion"
"between objects of different classes.\n\n"

"Unit IV:\n\n"
        "Inheritance: Derived class and Base class; Specifying the derived class accessing base class"
"members, the protected access specifier, Derived class constructor , overloading member functions,"
"public and private inheritance, Access Combinations, classes-structures , Access Specifiers , level of"
"inheritance ;multiple inheritance, hybrid inheritance , multilevel inheritance; Member functions in"
"multiple inheritance, constructors in multiple inheritance, container ship, classes within classes,"
"inheritance and program development.\n\n"


"Unit V:\n\n"
        "Virtual Functions: Normal member function accessed with pointers, Virtual member function"
"accessed with pointers, Dynamic binding, pure virtual functions, friends for functional notation, friend"
"classes, the this pointer, Accessing Member Data with this, using this for returning values. Templates"
"and Exception Handling: Introduction, template, class templates, function templates, member"
"functions template, template arguments, Exception Handling"
"Streams: The stream class hierarchy, stream classes Header file, string I/O, Writing strings, reading"
"strings, character I/O, detecting End of file, Objects I/O writing an object to disk, reading an object from"
"disk I/O with multiple objects; the istream class, The open function, File pointers; specifying the offset ,"
"The tellg function, disk I/O with memory Functions, closing Files , Error handling , command Line"
"arguments.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="dms1">
       "Unit I:\n\n"
        "Fundamentals and Counting: Sets and subsets, set operations, Sequences, Division in the"
"Integers, Matrices and Mathematical Structures. Permutations and Combinations, Pigeonhole"
"Principle, Elements of Probability, Recurrence Relations.\n\n"
"Unit II:\n\n"
        "Fundamentals of Logic: Basic connectives and truth tables, Logical equivalence, the laws of"
"logic, logical implication, rules of interface, use of quantifiers, quantifiers definition and proofs of"
"Theorems.\n\n"
"Unit III:\n\n"
        "Properties of Integers and Mathematical Induction: The well ordering principle,"
"Mathematical induction, Recursive definitions, the division algorithm, prime numbers, the GCD, Euclid’s"
"algorithm, the fundamental theorem of Arithmetic.\n\n"
"Unit IV:\n\n"
        "Relations and Digraphs: Products set and partitions, Relations and diagraphs, relations and"
"digraph , Paths in relations and digraphs ,properties of relations ,equivalence relations , computer"
"representation of relations and digraphs , operations on relations.\n\n"
"Unit V:\n\n"
        "Functions: Functions, functions for computer science, growth of function, permutation"
functions\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="unix1">
        "Unit I: UNIX Architecture\n\n"
"History of UNIX, UNIX Architecture, Features of UNIX, Internal and External Commands. General"
"Purpose Utilities  man, cal, date, echo, printf, bc, script, mailx, passwd, uname, tty, sty.File" system -
"The file, The parent-child relationship, the home directory, Directory Commands—pwd, cd, mkdir,"
"rmdir, Absolute pathnames, Relative Path names, ls.\n\n"
"Unit II: File Handling Commands\n\n"
"File handling Commands—cat, cp, rm, mv, file, wc, od, comm ,diff ,"
"dos2unix,unix2dos,gzip,gunzip,tar,zip ,unzip. Basic file attributes ls -l , file ownership ,file"
"permissions  chmod changing file permissions, Directory permissions, changing file ownership"
"vi Editor  Different modes of vi editor: input mode, Ex mode and command mode, search and"
"replace.\n\n"
"Unit III: The Shell\n\n"
"The shell interpretive cycle, pattern matching-- the wild card, Escaping, the backlash (/),quoting,"
"redirection, /dev/null, /dev/tty: Two special files, Pipes, tee, command substitution, shell variables.The"
"process -- Process basics, ps , Mechanism of process creation, running jobs in background, nice,"
"Killing processes, Job Control, at and batch, cron, time commands"
"Customizing the Environment: Customizing the environment using variables, common environment"
"variables, command history.\n\n"
"Unit IV : Essential Shell Programming\n\n"
"Shell scripts, read, exit , Using Command Line Arguments, Logical Operators AND and OR, if conditional,"
"using test and [ ] to evaluate the expression, the case conditional ,expr, while: looping, for: looping"
"with a list, arrays: single dimensional , the here document , set and shift, trap, debugging the shell"
"scripts with set –X.\n\n"

"Unit V :More File attributes\n\n"
"File systems and Inodes, Hard links, symbolic link and ln,The directory,umask,Modification and access"
"times, find: Locating files. Simple Filters : pr, head, tail, cut, paste, sort, uniq, tr,"
"Filters Using Regular Expression - grep, basic regular expressions, extended regular expression ,"
"egrep, fgrep. Communication in unix –finger, mesg ,write ,talk ,wall ,news ,mail.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="pd1">
     "Unit I:\n\n"
        "Meaning and definition of personality : Personality development as a process, Importance of"
"pass, Importance of personality development , Theories of Personality, Psychological theory(Signed"
"Freud),Phenomenological theory (Car Rogers) Cognitive theory (George A Kelly) A trait factor –"
"Analytic approach(Raymond B. Cattel ), Psychosocial development theory(Erickson).\n\n"

"Unit II:\n\n"
        "Determinants of Personality: Physical, intellectual, Emotional, social, educational familial.\n\n"

"Unit III:\n\n"
        "The self-Concept: Individual as a self-sculptor, process of perception cognition and their"
"impact , Learning process, What is attitude, The process of attitude formation.\n\n"
"Unit IV:\n\n"
        "Communication and its importance: Process of Communication, written and oral"
"communication, process of listening body language or non verbal communication, the art of public"
"speaking.\n\n"
"Unit V:\n\n"
        "Leadership as a process: Working in a team , management of conflict , interpersonal and"
"intrapersonal intergroup , Profiles of great personalities , Career planning and role of career planning"
"and role of career planning in personality development , How to face personal interview and group"
"discussion.\n\n"
    </string>

    //THIRDSEM

    //FOURTHSEM

    <string name="daa1">
        "Unit I: Introduction:\n\n"
"Definition of algorithm, Characteristics of algorithm, Algorithm Specification, Performance"
"analysis.Divide and Conquer: General Method, Binary Search, Finding Maximum and"
"Minimum, Merge Sort, Quick Sort, Selection Sort, Strassen’s Matrix Multiplication.\n\n"

"Unit II: Greedy method:\n\n"
"General Method, Knapsack Problem, Job Sequencing With Deadline, Minimum Cost"
"Spanning Trees, Optimal Storage On Tapes, Optimal Merge Pattern, Single Source"
"Shortest Paths.\n\n"

"Unit III: Dynamic Programming:\n\n"
"Introduction To Graphs, Definition Types, Terms Related To Graph, General Method,"
"Multistage Graphs, All Pair Shortest Paths, Optimal Binary Search Trees, 0/1 –"
"Knapsack, The Traveling Salesperson Problem, Flow Shop Scheduling.\n\n"

"Unit IV: Basic Traversal and Search Techniques:\n\n"
"Techniques For Binary Trees, Techniques For Graphs, Connected Components and"
"Spanning Trees, AND/OR Graphs.\n\n"

"Unit V: Backtracking:\n\n"
"General Method, The 8 – Queens Problems, Sum Of Subsets, Graph Coloring,"
"Hamiltonian Cycle, Knapsack Problem.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="java1">
        "Unit I: Introduction to JAVA:\n\n"
"JAVA Evolution, Java History, Java features, How java differs from C and C++, Java"
"and Internet, Java and World Wide Web. Overview of JAVA Language: Introduction,"
"Simple Java Program, More of Java, An Application with Two Classes, Java Program"
"structure, Java Tokens, Java Statements, Implementing a Java Program, Java Virtual"
"Machine, Command Line Arguments, Programming Style. Constants, Variables and"
"Data Types: Constants, Variables, Data Types, Declaration of Variables, Giving Values"
"to Variables, Scope of variables, Symbolic Constants, Type Casting, Getting Values of"
"Variables, Standard Default Values, Operators and Expressions: Arithmetic Operators,"
"Relational Operators, Logical Operators, Bitwise Operators, Special Operators,"
"Arithmetic Expressions, Evaluation of Expressions, Precedence of Arithmetic Operators,"
"Type conversion and Associativity, Mathematical Functions. Decision Making and"
"Branching: Decision making with if Statement, Simple if Statement, The if...... else"
"Statement, Nesting of if..Else Statement, The else if Ladder, The Switch Statement, The"
"?: Operator. Decision Making and Looping: while Statement; do Statement, for"
"Statement, Jumps in Loops, Labeled Loops.\n\n"

"Unit II: Classes, Arrays, Strings and Vectors:\n\n"
"Classes, Objects and Methods: Introduction, Defining a Class, Adding Variables,"
"Adding methods, Creating Objects, Accessing Class Members, Constructors, Methods"
"Overloading, Static members, Nesting of Methods, Inheritance: Extending a Class"
"Overriding Methods, Final Variables and Methods, Finalizer Methods, Abstract Methods"
"and Classes, Visibility Control. Arrays, Strings and Vectors: Arrays, One –"
"Dimensional Arrays, Creating an Array, Two – Dimensional Arrays, Strings, Vectors,"
"Wrapper Classes.\n\n"

"Unit III: Interfaces, Packages and Multithreaded Programming:\n\n"
"Interfaces: Multiple Inheritance: Defining Interfaces, Extending Interfaces, Implementing"
"Interfaces, Accessing Interface Variable. Packages: Putting Classes together: Java"
"API Package, ,Using System Packages, Naming Conventions, Creating Packages,"
"Accessing a Package, Using a Packages, Adding a Class to a Package, Hiding Classes."
"Multithreaded Programming: Creating Threads, Extending the Thread Class, Using"
"Thread Methods, Stopping and Blocking a Thread, Life Cycle of a Thread, Thread"
"Exceptions, Thread Priority, Synchronization, Implementing the ‘Runnable’ Interface.\n\n"

"Unit IV: Managing Exceptions, Applet Programming:\n\n"
"Managing Errors and Exception: Types of Errors, Exceptions, Syntax of Exception"
"handling Code, Multiple Catch Statements, Using Finally Statement, Throwing Our Own"
"Exceptions. Applet Programming: Applets Differ from Applications, Preparing to Write"
"Applets, Building Applet Code, Applet Life Cycle, Creating an Executable applet,"
"Designing a Web Page, Applet Tag, Adding Applet to HTML File, Running The Applet,"
"More about Applet Tag, Passing Parameters to Applets, Aligning the Display, More"
"About HTML Tags, Displaying Numerical Values, Getting Input from the User.\n\n"
"Unit V: Graphics Programming, Input / Output: Graphics Programming:\n\n"
"The Graphics Class, Lines and rectangles, circles and Ellipses, Drawing Arcs, Drawing"
"Polygons, Line Graphs, Using Control Loops in Applets, Drawing Bar Charts. Managing"
"Input / Output in JAVA: Concept of Streams, Stream Classes, Byte Stream Classes,"
"Character Stream Classes, Using Streams. Other Useful I/O Classes, Using the File"
"Class, Input/Output Exceptions, Creation of Files, Reading/Writing Characters,"
"Reading/Writing Bytes, Handling Primitive Data Types, Concatenating and Buffering"
"Files, Interactive Input and Output, Other Stream Classes.\n\n"

"Unit V: Graphics Programming, Input / Output: Graphics Programming:\n\n"
"The Graphics Class, Lines and rectangles, circles and Ellipses, Drawing Arcs, Drawing"
"Polygons, Line Graphs, Using Control Loops in Applets, Drawing Bar Charts. Managing"
"Input / Output in JAVA: Concept of Streams, Stream Classes, Byte Stream Classes,"
"Character Stream Classes, Using Streams. Other Useful I/O Classes, Using the File"
"Class, Input/Output Exceptions, Creation of Files, Reading/Writing Characters,"
"Reading/Writing Bytes, Handling Primitive Data Types, Concatenating and Buffering"
"Files, Interactive Input and Output, Other Stream Classes.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="vb1">
        "Unit I: Visual Basic .NET and the .NET Framework:\n\n"
"Introduction to .net framework -Features, Common Language Runtime (CLR) , Framework"
"Class Library(FCL), Visual Studio.Net – IDE, Languages Supported, Components."
"Visual Programming, VB.net- Features,"
"IDE- Menu System, Toolbars, Code Designer,"
"Solution Explorer, Object Browser, Toolbox, Class View Window, Properties Window,"
"Server Explorer, Task List, Output Window, Command Window.\n\n"

"Unit II: Elements of Visual Basic .net:\n\n"
"Properties, Events and Methods of Form, Label, TextBox, ListBox, Combo Box, Radio"
"Button, Button, Check Box, Progress Bar, Date Time Picker, Calendar, Picture Box,"
"HScrollbar, VScrollBar, Group Box, ToolTip, Timer.\n\n"

"Unit III: Programming in Visual basic .net:\n\n"
"Data Types, Keywords, Declaring Variables and Constants, Operators, Understanding"
"Scope and accessibility of variables, Conditional Statements- If- Then, If-Then-Else,"
"Nested If, Select Case, Looping Statement- Do loop, For Loop, For Each-Next Loop, While"
"Loop, Arrays- Static and Dynamic.\n\n"

"Unit IV: Functions, Built-In Dialog Boxes, Menus and Toolbar:\n\n"
"Menus and toolbars- Menu Strip, Tool Strip, Status Strip, Built-In Dialog Boxes – Open File"
"Dialogs, Save File Dialogs, Font Dialogs, Color Dialogs, Print Dialogs, InputBox, MsgBox,"
"Interfacing With End user- Creating MDI Parent and Child, Functions and Procedures-"
"Built-In Functions- Mathematical and String Functions, User Defined Functions and"
"Procedures.\n\n"

"Unit V: Advanced Concepts in VB.Net:\n\n"
"Object Oriented Programming- Creating Classes , Objects, Fields, Properties, Methods,"
"Events,"
"Constructors and destructors, Exception Handling- Models, Statements, File"
"Handling- Using File Stream Class, File Mode, File Share, File Access Enumerations,"
"Opening or Creating Files with File Stream Class, Reading and Writing Text using"
"StreamReader and StreamWriter Classes"
"Data Access with ADO.Net – Database, Data Access with Server Explorer, Data Adapter"
"and DataSets, ADO.NET Objects and Basic SQL.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="it1">
       "Unit I: Introduction to IT Infrastructure:\n\n"
"IT Infrastructure Management, Challenges, Design Issues of IT Organizations and IT"
"Infrastructure, Determining Customer’s Requirements, IT Systems Management Process, IT"
"Service Management Process, Information System Design Process, Patterns for IT Systems"
"Management, IT Infrastructure Library\n\n"

"Unit II: Service Delivery Process:\n\n"
"Service Level Management, Financial Management, IT Service Continuity Management,"
"Capacity Management, Availability Management\n\n"

"Unit III: Service Support Process:\n\n"
"Configuration Management, Incident"
"Management, Problem Management,"
"Management, Release Management"
"Change\n\n"

"Unit IV: Storage and Security Management:\n\n"
"Storage Management: Introduction to Storage, Backup and Storage, Archive and Retrieve,"
"Disaster Recovery, Space Management, Database and Application Protection, Bare"
"Machine Recovery, Data Retention. Security Management: Computer Security, Internet"
"Security, Physical Security, Identity Management, Access Control System, Intrusion"
"Detection.\n\n"

"Unit V: IT Ethics and Emerging Trends in IT:\n\n"
"It Ethics: Intellectual Property, Privacy and Law, Computer Forensics, Ethics and Internet,"
"Cyber Crime, Emerging Trends in IT: E-Commerce, Electronic Data Interchange (EDI),"
"GSM, Bluetooth, Infrared Technology.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="se1">
        "UNIT 1: Introduction:\n\n"
"Professional development, software engineering ethics, Software processes – software"
"process models-"
"Waterfall Model, Incremental development, reuse oriented Software"
"engineering, Software process activities Prototyping, Boehm’s spiral model. Requirement"
"Engineering – Functional and non functional requirement, Software requirements"
"document, requirements specification, Requirements engineering process, Requirements"
"elicitation and analysis, requirements validation, Requirements management.\n\n"

"UNIT 2: System Models:\n\n"
"Context models, Interaction models, Behavioral model, Functional modeling and"
"Information flow – Data flow diagram, Data dictionary.\n\n"

"UNIT 3: Architectural Design and Implementation:\n\n"
"Architectural design decisions, architectural views, architectural patterns Design and"
"Implementation – Object oriented design using UML, Design patterns, Implementation"
"issues, Open source development.\n\n"

"UNIT 4: Dependability engineering and security engineering"
"Redundancy and diversity, Dependable processes, dependable architecture, dependable"
"programming, Security Engineering – Security risk management, Design for security,"
"System survivability.\n\n"

"UNIT 5: Project Management and Planning:\n\n"
"Risk management, Managing people, Teamwork, Project planning- Plan driven"
"development, Project scheduling, Estimation techniques.\n\n"
    </string>

    //FOURTHSEM

    //FIFTHSEM

    <string name="os1">
"Unit I: Introduction:\n\n"
"Batch Systems, Concepts of Multiprogramming and Time Sharing, Parallel, Distributed and real time Systems, Operating System Structures, Components and"
"Services. Process Management: Process concept, Process scheduling, Co-operating"
"process, Threads, Inter process communication, CPU scheduling criteria, Scheduling"
"algorithm.\n\n"
"Unit II: Process synchronization and deadlocks:\n\n"
"The critical section problem, Synchronization hardware, Semaphores, Classical problems of synchronization, Critical"
"regions, monitors, Dead locks –System model , characterization, Dead lock prevention,"
"avoidance and detection, Recovery from dead lock.\n\n"
"Unit III: Memory Management:\n\n"
"Logical and Physical address space, Swapping Contiguous allocation, Paging, Segmentation, Virtual memory – Demand paging and it’s performance,"
"page replacement algorithms, Allocation of frames, thrashing\n"
"Unit IV: File management (System, Secondary storage structure):\n\n"
"File concepts, Access methods, Directory structure, Protection and consistency, semantics, File system structure,"
"Allocation methods, Free space management\n\n"
"Unit V: Disk Management (Structure, Disk Scheduling Methods):\n"
"Disk structure and Scheduling methods , Disk management, Swap – Space management. Protection and"
"Security: Goals of protection, Domain protection, Access matrix security problem,"
"Authentication, One time password.\n\n"

    </string>

    <string name="wp1">
       "Unit I: Fundamentals of Web, XHTML and CSS\n\n"
"Internet, WWW, Web Browsers, and Web Servers, URLs, MIME,HTTP, The Web"
"Programmers Toolbox, XHTML- Basic Syntax, Standard structure, Basic text markup,"
"Images, Hypertext, Links, Lists, Tables, Forms, Frames, CSS- Introduction, Levels of style"
"sheets, Selector forms, Property value forms, Font properties, Color, Alignment of text, The"
"box model, Background images, The span and div tags.\n\n"

"Unit II :Javascript\n\n"
"Overview of Javascript, Syntactic characterstics, Primitives, operations, and expressions,"
"Screen output and keyboard input, Control statements,Object creation and modification,"
"Arrays, Functions, Constructor, Pattern matching using regular expressions, Errors in"
"scripts, Examples. Event and event Handling , Handling events from body elements, Button"
"elements, Text box and Password elements.\n\n"

"Unit III: ASP.NET\n\n"
"File types in ASP.NET 3.5,Exploring ASP.NET 3.5 Web Pages, Understanding ASP.NET 3.5"
"Page Directives, Understanding ASP.NET 3.5 Provider Model, ASP.NET Coding Models,"
"Implementing Code Sharing, Compilation in ASP.NET 3.5. Application Structure and State:"
"Structure of an Application, The Global.asax application File, Using States,Http Handlers,"
"Postback\n\n"

"Unit IV: Web Forms Controls\n\n"
"The control class, The web control class, Using CSS in Web Application, Web Server"
"Controls: Label, Button, Textbox , Literal, Place Holder ,Hidden Field, File Upload, Image"
",Image Map, ListBox, Drop Down List, Hyperlink, Link Button, CheckBox, Radio Buttons,"
"User Controls and Custom Controls, Validation Controls: Required Field Validator,"
"Range Validator, Regular Expression Validator, Compare Validator, Custom Validator,"
"Validation Summary.\n\n"

"Unit V: Data Access With ADO.NET\n\n"
"Introducing Databases,Introduction to SQL,ADO.Net, Understanding the of"
"ADO.NET,Creating Connection Strings and Connection to Databases,Command Object and"
"Data Adapters, Database Contorls: Data Grid View Control,Data List Controls and Details"
"View Controls.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="dbms1">
        "Unit I: Introduction:\n\n"
        "Database and Database Users, Characteristics of the Database"
"Approach, Actors on the scene, Workers behind the Scene, Advantages of using DBMS,"
"Brief History. Database System Concepts and Architecture: Data Models, Schemas,"
"and Instances, Three Schema Architecture and Data Independence, Database language"
"and interfaces, the database system Environment, Centralized and Client/Server"
"Architectures for DBMS, Classification of Database Management Systems.\n\n"

"Unit II: Data modelling using the Entity–Relationship(ER) model:\n\n"
"High level conceptual data models for database design with an example, Entity types, Entity sets,"
"Attributes and Keys, Relationship types, Relationship sets, Roles and Structural"
"Constraints, Weak Entity Types, ER Diagrams, Naming Conventions, and Design"
"Issues, Relationship types of degree higher than two.\n\n"

"Unit 3: Relational Data Model and Relational Algebra:\n\n"
"Relation Data Model and"
"Relational Database Constraints, Relation Algebra, Relational Database Design by ER"
"and EER to Relational Mapping.\n\n"

"Unit 4: Functional dependencies and Normalization for Relational Databases:\n\n"
"Informal Design Guidelines for Relational Schemas, Functional Dependencies, Normal"
"Forms based on Primary Keys, General Definition of 2NF and 3NF, Boyce-Codd Normal"
"Form(BCNF).\n\n"

"Unit 5: Relational Database Language:\n\n"
"Data definition in SQL, Queries in SQL, Insert,"
"Delete and Update Statements in SQL, Views in SQL, Specifying General Constraints as"
"Assertions, Specifying indexes, Embedded SQL. Transaction Processing Concepts:"
"Introduction, Transaction and System Concepts, Desirable properties of transaction,"
"Schedules and Recoverability, Serializability of Schedules, Transaction Support in SQL,"
"Locking Techniques for Concurrency Control\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="cn1">
"Unit I: Introduction:\n\n"
"Computer Networks and its applications, Network structure,"
"network architecture, Topologies, LAN, WAN, MAN, The OSI reference model, The"
"TCP/IP reference model, services, network standards, example networks. The Physical"
"Layer: Transmission Media – Twisted pair, coaxial cable, optical fiber, radio"
"transmission, microwaves and infrared transmission, Switching – message switching"
"Circuit switching, packet switching.\n\n"

"Unit II: The Data Link Layer:\n\n"
"Data Link Layer design issues, Error detection – Single parity checking,"
"polynomial codes – CRC, Error correction- Hamming code, Elementary"
"data link protocols, sliding window protocols, Example data link protocols.\n\n"

"Unit III: The Medium Access Control:\n\n"
"The channel allocation problem, multiple access"
"protocols – ALOHA, Slotted ALOHA, CSMA protocols, Collision free protocols, Ethernet,"
"Wireless LAN, Bluetooth.\n\n"

"Unit IV: The network Layer:\n\n"
"Network layer design issues, Routing algorithms –"
"Flooding, Distance vector routing , Hierarchical routing, Link state routing, Congestion"
"control algorithms – Leaky bucket, token bucket algorithm, admission control, hop by hop"
"choke packets , Quality of Service.\n\n"

"Unit V: The Transport Layer and Application Layer:\n\n" Transport service, Elements of"
"Transport protocols, Internet transport protocols (TCP and UDP), DNS, Electronic Mailing,"
"and World Wide Web.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="cnet1">
"Unit I:The Philosophy of .NET:\n\n"
"The .NET Solution, Introducing the Building Blocks of the"
".NET Platform (CLR,CTS, and CLS), An Overview of .NET Assemblies, C# Language"
"Fundamentals. Anatomy, The System.Environment Class, Defining Classes and Creating"
"objects, The System.Console Class, Member Visibility, Default Values of Class Member"
"Variables, Member Variable Initialization Syntax, Defining Constant Data, Defining Read-"
"only fields, Understanding the static keyword, Method Parameter Modifiers, Iteration"
"Types and Reference Types, Understanding Boxing and Unboxing Operations, Working with"
".NET Enumerations, The Master Class: System.Object, Overridding some default"
"behaviours of System.Object, The System Data types( and C# Shorthand notation), The"
"System.String data types, The role of System.Text, StringBuilder, .NET Array Types,"
"Understanding C# Nullable Types, Defining Custom Namespaces.\n\n"

"Unit II: Object- Oriented Programming :\n\n"
"Understanding the C# Class Type, Reviewing the"
"Pillars of OOP, C#’s Encapsulation Services, C#’s Inheritance Support, Programming for"
"Containment/Delegation, C #’s Polymorphic Support, C# Casting rules, Understanding C#"
"Partial types, Documenting C# Source Code via XML. Understanding Object Lifetime"
"Classes, Objects and References, the basics of Object Lifetime, System.GC type, Building"
"Finalizable Objects, Building Disposable Objects.\n\n"

"Unit III:Exception Handling:\n\n"
"Ode to Errors, Bugs, and Exceptions, The Role of .NET"
"Exception Handing, The Simplest possible example, throwing generic exceptions, catching"
"exceptions, Configuring the state of an exception-Target Site , Stack trace, Helplink and data"
"property. System – Level Exception (System.Exception), Application-Level Exception"
"(System.ApplicationException), Processing Multiple Exception, Generic catch statements,"
"Rethrowing exceptions, Inner exceptions, The Finally Block\n\n"

"Unit IV: Interfaces, Collections, Delegates and Events:\n\n"
"Defining Interfaces in C#,"
"Implementing an Interface in C#, Contrasting Interfaces to Abstract Base Classes, Invoking"
"Interface Members at the Object Level, Interfaces As Parameters, Interfaces As Return"
"Values, Arrays of Interfaces Types, Understanding Explicit Interface Implementation,"
"Building Interface Hierarchies, The Interfaces of the System.Collections Namespace, .NET"
"Delegate type, Defining a Delegate in C#, The System.MulticastDelegate and"
"System.Delegate Base Classes, Delegate examples, C# Events, Anonymous Method, C#"
"Method Group Conversions.\n\n"

"Unit V: Understanding .NET Assemblies and Libraries:\n\n"
"The Role of .NET Assemblies,"
"Understanding the format of .NET Assemblies, Building and Consuming a Single- File"
"Assembly, Building and Consuming a Multi-File Assembly, Shared Assemblies, The System"
"IO Namespace, Directory (Info) and File (Info) types, Working with DirectoryInfo, Directory"
"Type, FileInfo, File Type Classes, Abstract Stream Class, StreamWriters"
"StreamReaders, StringWriters and StringReaders, BinaryWriters and BinaryReaders.\n\n"
    </string>

    //FIFTHSEM

    //SIXTHSEM

    <string name="spt1">
        "UNIT I:Principles of Testing, Software Development Life Cycle Models (SDLC), Phases of"
"Software Project, Quality, Quality Assurance and Quality Control, Testing, Verification and"
"Validation, Life Cycle Models, White Box Testing: White Box Testing, Static Testing, Structural"
"Testing, Challenges in White Box Testing.\n\n"

"UNIT II: Testing Techniques: Black Box Testing, Integration Testing, Top-Down Integration,"
"Bottom-Up Integration, Bi-Directional Integration, Defect Bash, System and Acceptance Testing,"
"Functional versus Non-functional Testing, Functional System Testing, Non-Functional System"
"Testing, Acceptance Testing.\n\n"

"UNIT III: Performance Testing: Factors, Methodology, Tools, Process for performance testing,"
"Regression Testing, Types, Testing of Object-oriented Systems, Usability and"
"AccessibilityTesting, approach, Quality factors, Aesthetics Testing, Accessibility Testing, Tools"
"for Usability.\n\n"

"UNIT IV: Common People Issues: Perceptions and Misconceptions About Testing,"
"comparison between Testing and Development Functions, Providing Career Paths for Testing"
"Professionals, The role of the Ecosystem and a call for Action. Organization Structures for"
"testing teams: Dimensions of Organization Structures, Structures in Single product"
"Companies, Structures for Multi-Product Companies. (14.1 to 14.3).\n\n"

"UNIT V: Test Planning, Management: Test Planning: Preparation, scope management, Test"
"approach, setting up criteria, Identifying responsibilities, test deliveries, testing tasks, activity"
"breakdown, communication and risk management. Test Management: Choice of standards,"
"Test Infrastructure Management, Integrating with Product release. (15.1 to 15.3) Software Test"
"Automation: Introduction, Terms used, Skills needed, scope of automation: Identifying the"
"types of testing amenable to automation.(16.1 to 16.4.1)\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="bi1">
        "Unit I: Business View of Information Technology applications:\n\n"
        "Business Enterprise"
"Organization , Its functions, and core business process, baldrige business excellence frame"
"work (Optional reading) Key purpose of using IT in business, The connected world :"
"Characteristics of Internet _Ready IT Applications, Enterprise applications(ERP/CRM) and"
"bespoke IT applications, information users and their requirements, Types of digital data ,"
"structured data , unstructured data, Semi-structured data , Difference between semi structured"
"and structured data.\n\n"

"Unit II: Introduction to OLTP and OLAP :\n\n"
        "OLTP(online transaction processing) OLAP(online"
"Analytical Processing) Different OLAP Architectures , OLTP and OLAP, Data models for OLTP"
"and OLAP, Role of OLAP tools in the BI Architecture , should OLAP be performed directly on"
"operational data bases. Business intelligence: Using analytical information of decision"
"support, Information sources before dawn of BI , BI defined , evolution of BI and role of DSS ,"
"EIS, MIS and digital dash boards, Need for BI at virtually all levels , BI for past , present and"
"future, The BI value Chain , Introduction to Business analytics.\n\n"

"Unit III:BI definitions and concepts : BI component Framework , BI Users, Business"
"Intelligence Applications, BI roles and responsibilities, Basics of data integration , Need for"
"data Warehouse ,Definition of data Warehouse, ODS, Ralph Kimball’s Approach vsInmon’s"
"Approach , Goals of data warehouse, Constituents of data Warehouse , Data integration, Data"
"integration technologies , Data Quality , Data Profiling, A case Study from the Healthcare"
"Domain.\n\n"

"Unit IV:Types of Data Model:Data Modelling techniques, Fact table, Dimension table, Typical"
"dimensional Models, Dimensional Modelling Life cycle, Understanding Measures and"
"performance measurement System terminology , navigating a Business Enterprise.\n\n"

"Unit V:Basics of Enterprise Reporting: Reporting perspectives common to all levels of"
"Enterprise, Report Standardization"
"and Presentation practices, Enterprise Reporting"
"characteristics in OLAP World , Balanced score card , Dash boards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="j2ee1">
"Unit I: Swings :\n\n"
"The origins of Swing; Two key features; MVC Connection; Components and"
"Containers, The Swing Packages; A simple Swing application; Create a Swing Applet; Jlabel"
"and ImageIcon; JTextField; The Swing Buttons; JTabbedpane; JScrollPane; JList; JComboBox;"
"JTable, DesktopPane and JInternalFrames.\n\n"

"Unit II: Java 2 Enterprise Edition Overview, Database Access:\n\n"
"The Concept of JDBC;"
"JDBC Driver Types; JDBC Packages; A Brief Overview of the JDBC process; Database"
"Connection; Associating the JDBC/ODBC Bridge with the Database; Statement Objects;"
"ResultSet; Transaction Processing; Metadata, Data types; Exceptions\n\n"

"Unit III: Servlets, JSP :\n\n"
"Background; The Life Cycle of a Servlet; Using Tomcat for Servlet"
"Development; A simple Servlet; The Servlet API; The Javax. servlet Package; Reading Servlet"
"Parameter; The Javax.servlet.http package; Handling HTTP Requests and Responses; Using"
"Cookies; Session Tracking. Java Server Pages (JSP): JSP, JSP Tags, Tomcat, Request"
"String, User Sessions, Cookies, Session Objects.\n\n"

"Unit IV: Networking and RMI:\n\n"
"Networking Basics, Classes and Interfaces, Inet Address,"
"TCP/IP Client Sockets, Server Sockets, URL , URL Connection, HttpURLConnection, The URL"
"Class, Cookies, Datagrams, Java Remote Method Invocation: Remote Method Invocation"
"concept; Server side, Client side\n\n"

"Unit V: Enterprise Java Beans :\n\n"
"Enterprise java Beans; Deployment Descriptors; Session"
"Java Bean, Entity Java Bean; Message-Driven Bean; The JAR File.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="lab1">
"J2EE Lab Assignments\n\n"
"1. Write a JAVA Swing Program to create a MDI form and child forms.\n"
"2. Write a JAVA Program to insert data into Student DATA BASE and retrieve info base on"
"particular queries\n"
"3. Write a JAVA Servlet Program to implement a dynamic HTML using Servlet (user name"
"and password should be accepted using HTML and displayed using a Servlet).\n"
"4. Write a JAVA Servlet Program to Download a file and display it on the screen (A link has"
"to be provided in HTML, when the link is clicked corresponding file has to be displayed"
"on Screen)\n"
"5. Write a JAVA Servlet Program to implement and demonstrate get() and Post"
"methods(Using HTTP Servlet Class).\n"
"6. Write a JAVA Servlet Program to implement sendRedirect() method(using HTTP Servlet"
"Class)\n"
"7. Write a JAVA Program to establish the client and server communication using TCP/IP"
"socket.\n"
"8. Write a JAVA JSP Program to print 10 even and 10 odd number.\n\n"
"Software Testing Lab Assignments\n\n"
"1. Write a program(C/C++/Java) to test the following constructs.\n"
"a. do...while\n"
"b. if...else\n"
"c. for loop\n"
"2. Black Box testing: (Functional Testing) Design a login web page and test the same.\n"
"3. Black Box testing: (Functional Testing and performance Testing with database)"
"Design a Web page to update the student record into the database and test the same.\n"
"4. Black Box testing: (Functional Testing and performance Testing )"
"Design a web page to provide the total number of objects present / available on the page"
"and test the same.\n"
"5. Black Box testing: (Load Testing )"
"Design a web page to get the count of visitors who visit your web page.\n"
"6. White Box Testing: Code Coverage- JaCoCo
"Write a Java program to compute the factorial of a given non-negative number using:\n"
"a. Iterative Process\n"
"b. Recursion\n"
"Produce the Coverage Information using the JaCoCo toolGuidelines for Software Testing Lab Assignments "
"Introduction to Selenium IDE: (http://docs.seleniumhq.org/docs/02_selenium_ide.jsp)"
"The Selenium-IDE (Integrated Development Environment) is the tool you use to develop your"
"Selenium test cases. It’s an easy-to-use Firefox plug-in and is generally the most efficient way"
"to develop test cases. It also contains a context menu that allows you to first select a UI element"
"from the browser’s currently displayed page and then select from a list of Selenium commands"
"with parameters pre-defined according to the context of the selected UI element. This is not only"
"a time-saver, but also an excellent way of learning Selenium script syntax."
"Selenium Server (formerly the Selenium RC Server)"
"The Selenium Server is needed in order to run either Selenium RC style scripts or Remote"
"Selenium Webdriver ones. The 2.x server is a drop-in replacement for the old Selenium RC"
"server and is designed to be backwards compatible with your existing infrastructure .\n\n"
"Configuration Needed:\n"
"JDK 1.6 or above\n"
"Selenium IDE (http://docs.seleniumhq.org/docs/02_selenium_ide.jsp)\n"
"Eclipse for Java or Netbeans\n"
"Selenium RC Server (http://docs.seleniumhq.org/download/)\n"
"(Down load Selenium Client drivers of java, we will get Selenium Server v2.1xxx.zip file)\n"
"firebug (http://getfirebug.com)\n"
"Apache Tomcat 6 (http://apache.org)\n"
    </string>

    <string name="project1">
 "Project guidelines:\n"
"1. The project shall be carried out in a team of minimum of 2 members or maximum of three"
"students.\n"
"2. The team has to give three seminars on their project work focusing on the following aspect:\n"
"a. Synopsis / Problem Definition\n"
"b. System Requirement Specifications (SRS)\n"
"c. Design – High Level ,Low Level\n"
"3. Students shall submit the weekly progress report to their allotted internal guides.\n\n"
"Evaluation\n"
"A. Internal Assessment:\n"
"The project shall be evaluated for\n"
"a) Synopsis : 5 Marks\n"
"b) SRS Document as per IEEE format:5 marks\n"
"c) Design :20 marks\n"
"(i) High Level Design\n"
"(ii) Low Level Design\n"
"d) Coding and Testing :20 marks\n"
"e) Report :10 marks\n"
"B. Final Examination:\n"
"The final examination shall be evaluated on the following guidelines.\n"
"Project Report : 30 Marks\n"
"Presentation: 30 Marks\n"
"Demonstration : 90 Marks\n"
"Viva-Voce: 30 Marks\n"
"Modifications: 60 Marks\n\n"
"The following suggested guidelines must be followed in preparing the Final project"
"Report:\n\n"
"Good quality white executive bond paper A4 size should be used for typing and duplication.\n"
"Care should be taken to avoid smudging while duplicating the copies.\n"
"Page Specification :(Written paper and source code)\n"
" Left margin - 3.0 cms\n"
" Right margin- 2.0 cms\n"
" Top margin 2.54 cms\n"
" Bottom margin 2.54 cms\n"
" Page numbers - All text pages as well as Program source code listing should be"
"numbered at the bottom center of the pages.\n"
"Normal Body Text: Font Size: 12, Times New Roman, Double Spacing, Justified. 6 point"
"above and below para spacing\n"
"Paragraph Heading Font Size: 14, Times New Roman, Underlined, Left Aligned. 12 point"
"above and below spacing\n"
"Chapter Heading Font Size: 20, Times New Roman, Centre Aligned, 30 point above and"
"below spacing.\n"
"Coding Font size :10, Courier New, NormalSubmission of Project Report to the University :The student will submit his/her project report"
"in the prescribed format. The Project Report should include:\n"
"1. One copy of the synopsis.\n
"2. One hard Copy of the Project Report.\n"
"3. Soft copy of project on CD in a thick envelope pasted inside of the back cover of the project\n"
"report.\n"
"4. The Project Report may be about 75 pages (excluding coding).\n\n"
"FORMAT OF THE STUDENT PROJECT REPORT ON COMPLETION OF THE PROJECT\n"
" Cover Page as per format\n"
" Acknowledgement\n"
" Certificate of the project guide/Centre Manager as at Annexure III\n"
" Certificate of the Company/Organization (for direct candidates)\n"
" Synopsis of the Project\n"
" Main Report\n"
" Objective and Scope of the Project\n"
" theoretical Background Definition of Problem\n"
" System Analysis and Design\n"
" User Requirements System Planning (PERT Chart)\n"
" Methodology adopted\n"
" System Implementation and Details ofHardware and Software used.\n"
" System Maintenance and Evaluation\n"
" Cost and benefit Analysis\n"
" Detailed Life Cycle of the Project\n"
" ERD, DFD\n"
" Input and output screen design\n"
" Process involved\n"
" Methodology used for testing\n"
" Test Report, Printout of the Reports and print out of the Code Sheet\n"
" User/Operational Manual - including security aspects, access rights, back up, controls, etc.\n\n"
"Annexure:\n"
"1. Brief background of the organization where the student has developed the project.\n"
"2. Data Dictionary (This should give a catalogue of the data elements used in the system / sub"
"system developed. The following are the details required. Write NA if NOT applicable:\n"
"Data Name, Aliases, if any Length (Size) Type, Numeric, Alpha, Binary etc.\n"
"3. List of abbreviations, Figures, Tables\n"
"4. References Bibliography Website\n"
"5. Soft copy of the project on CD/DVD.\n"
    </string>


</resources>
